Chatdanai Lumdee, PhD

- -- A lifelong learner. Physicist turned data scientist. Building his mastery towards data-driven society.
- -- Website: clumdee.github.io

SUMMARY

Chatdanai started his career as an optical scientist with specialization in nanophotonics. His research produced a record of publications in top-tier scientific journals and presentations at international conferences.*

He later developed proficiency in data science with skills in data analytics, machine learning, and big data technology.** His expertise leads him to join top tech firms in Southeast Asia across different fields. Delivering data solutions that help improve decision making, marketing, and operation efficiency.



EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Senior Data Analyst 08/2020 - present 08/2019 - 08/2020

Data Science, Agoda (part of Booking Holdings) - Bangkok, Thailand

- Anomaly detection service, preventing booking losses in all channels across platform
 - o Implement a robust algorithm that auto-scales with traffic and is adaptive across all channels
- Fraud prevention using data analytics and machine learning, saving millions USD annually
 - Develop machine learning models to identify high risk bookings, track the performance with fraud agents, support models integration, monitor and update models
 - Improve human-machine communication for real-time fraud prevention by integrating machine learning jobs and alert bot to notify fraud agents
 - Automate workflow to evaluate fraud prevention protocols with high-level summary and real-time dashboard for the operation team to track their performance and to improve their protocols
 - Implement tools to improve working efficiency, e.g. ML Health, Feature Store, and share knowledge with other teams

Data Scientist (Digital Consultant)

09/2018 - 08/2019

Applied Intelligence, Accenture Digital, Accenture – Bangkok, Thailand

- AI-Powered Call Center [Business Dev]: off-load queue with speech recognition and call deflection
- **Personalized Wealth Management** [Business Dev]: customer segmentation for investment products
- **Digital Lending (Analytics Workstream)**, Leading Thai Bank

09/2018 - 05/2019

- Coordinated with marketing team to co-create personalized emotive message at mass using micro-segment by transforming multi-dimensional data into easy to understand customer profiles
- Coordinated with internal teams to integrate 3rd party data with internal data to enable targeting both existing and non-bank customers
- Tracked campaign's feedback and created dashboards to support project planning and optimization
- Served as an analytics contact point for operation personnel up to management ensuring our lead generating solutions to work at their best, operationally and strategically

^{*}Links for publications and presentations.

^{**}Some side projects on website and GitHub e.g. Home Weather Station with Azure Cloud.

Data Scientist 11/2017 – 08/2018

KLabs, Kasikorn Business-Technology Group (KBTG) - Bangkok, Thailand

• **Personal Investment Recommendation:** Built a machine learning model to integrate with Kplus. Offering the 1st national scale app-based intelligent mutual fund recommendation to > 8M users.

Research Scientist (Postdoctoral)

04/2016 - 10/2017

Department of Physics, University of Gothenburg/Chalmers – Gothenburg, Sweden

- **Next Generation Data Storage Technology**: We explored the interplay between nanoscale optics and magnetism with the aim to develop a technological platform for the next generation of data storage units (European Union's EU Horizon2020 program).
 - Developed protocols to produce both stationary and transferable hybrid magnetic-metallic nanostructure arrays -- introducing nanoscale magneto-optical interaction on any type of substrates
 - Designed and set up hardware control system (LabVIEW) to automate measurement and data collection -- enabling large scale and continuous data collection
 - Conducted numerical 3D electromagnetic simulations -- designing, confirming, and understanding experimental data

Research Scientist (PhD Candidate)

08/2010 - 01/2016

CREOL/The College of Optics and Photonics - Orlando, Florida, USA

- Optical Interactions at the Nanoscale: This research area is the core foundation of several emerging technologies including single-molecular sensing, surface enhanced photocatalysis, and heat-assisted magnetic recording.
 - Designed and set up experiments to capture optical responses at single nanoparticle level
 - Developed new approaches to interactively control optical interaction between nanoparticles and metallic substrates
 - Conducted numerical 3D electromagnetic simulations -- designing, confirming, and understanding experimental data

TECHNICAL STACKS

Data Analytics: Python, PySpark, SQL, Matlab, Origin, Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, Grafana, Metabase,

Microsoft Azure, Azure Databricks

Web Dev: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Django (sample work)

Others: Optical experiment and simulation, nanofabrication,

materials characterization, hardware system control (LabVIEW)

Native Thai and fluent in English

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Optics and Photonics

08/2010 - 12/2015

CREOL/The College of Optics and Photonics, University of Central Florida – Orlando, Florida, USA *GPA:* 3.95/4.00

B.Eng. in **Nano-engineering** (major in Nanoelectronics)

08/2006 - 05/2010

Chulalongkorn University – Bangkok, Thailand *GPA: 3.91/4.00*, Graduated with First Class Honors